你确定她是说要来这里吗
You sure this is where she said she was going?
对  第九大道和珍街街角
Yeah, yeah 9th and Jane.
托瑞说还是追踪不到贝克特的电话
Tory said she still can't get a trace on Beckett's phone.
说不是被关机就是被毁了
Says it's either been turned off or disabled.
那里  那是她的车
There. There's her car.
救救她
"Help her!"
他们要我们知道他们抓走了她
They want us to know they have her.
-该死  -把鉴证组叫来
- Damn. - All right, let's get CSU down here!
全员出动  所有值勤警员全部进行搜索
Call in a 10-45! I want every available unit canvassing!
排查每一个人
Ask everyone questions!
肯定有人看到她了  开始行动
Somebody had to have seen her! Let's go!
我们要查看这一带所有的监控摄像头
We're gonna dig into all the security and traffic cams in the area...
所有提款机  商户  所有能看到街面的东西
Any ATMs, businesses, anything with eyes on the street.
行动
Go, go, go!
卡塞尔
Castle?
是他
It's him.
布德罗  泰森  不管他自称什么
Boudreau, Tyson, whatever he's calling himself...
是他  是尼曼
It's him, and it's Nieman.
但他们当时在分局啊
But they were in the precinct with us.
这样他们有完美的不在场证明
Giving them the perfect alibi.
却利用艾米·巴瑞特把贝克特引出来
Meanwhile, they use Amy Barrett as bait to draw Beckett out.
你觉得巴瑞特也有关
You think Barrett was involved with this?
或者她也是受害人
Or she's a victim, too.
我们得找到尼曼
We need to find Nieman,
我们得找到布德罗
and we need to find Boudreau.
布德罗先生  开门
Mr. Boudreau, open up!
布德罗先生  我们一位警探
Mr. Boudreau, shortly after leaving
离开去见你朋友艾米·巴瑞特
to meet with your friend Amy Barrett,
不久后便失踪了
one of our detectives went missing.
所以呢
So?
-她在哪  -我不知道
- So, where is she? - I don't know.
我直到一小时前才被释放
I've been in police custody until an hour ago.
这样你有了完美的不在场证明
Giving you the perfect alibi.
我有不在场证明或许是因为我没做什么错事
Maybe I have an alibi 'cause I didn't do anything wrong.
那为什么不让我们进去呢
Then why don't you let us in?
好啊
Fine.
贝克特
Beckett?
-贝克特  -拜托  这里没人  只有我
- Beckett?! - Come on, man. Nobody's here. It's just me.
你对她做了什么  泰森
What'd you do to her? Huh, Tyson?
你把她关在哪了
Where are you keeping her?
我没关她  而且我也不是杰瑞·泰森
I'm not keeping her anywhere, and I'm not Jerry Tyson.
不不  你别这样  你不能这样
No, no! Come on! You can't do this.
你不能跑进来威胁我
You can't just come in here threatening me.
我知道是你  我知道是你
I know it's you! I know it's you.
你这样帮不了她  这样不行
You're not helping her... not like that.
-怎么  我们就等着她被杀吗  -不
- So what? We just let him kill her? - No.
但是卡塞尔  我们如果没有证据
But, Castle, we can't do anything
就不能做什么
if we don't have anything.
是他  凯文  是泰森
It's him, Kevin. It's Tyson.
我们得证明
We need to prove it.
我们让警员跟踪他  盯死他
We'll put units on him, put him under the microscope.
如果是他
If it's him,
他的一举一动我们都会知道
he won't be able to make a move without us knowing it.
我们会找到她的
We'll find her.
随便你看吧  埃斯波西托警探
Okay, look all you want, detective Esposito,
她不在这里  我不知道她在哪里
She's not here, and I have no idea where she is.
那你的客户艾米·巴瑞特呢
What about your client Amy Barrett?
我们办公室已经将她的信息交给你们了
My office gave you our information on Amy Barrett.
我们的联络信息过期我也没办法
I can't help it if her contact information is out of date.
当然了  就像你跟贝克特探长的失踪
Yeah, I bet you can't... just like you have nothing to do with
也是毫无瓜葛
Detective Beckett's disappearance.
你似乎是对我有错误的看法
You seem to think that I'm something that I'm not.
我怎么可能与此有关
And how could I be involved?
我当时跟你们在一起
I was with you at the time.
我安排警员监视布德罗的住处
I got a unit on Boudreau's place
还有一辆跟踪车在待命
and a follow car standing by.
-埃斯波  也派人去监视尼曼  -是
- Espo, put units on Nieman, as well. - Copy that.
排查有什么发现吗
Anything on the canvass?
我们已经抽调了三区和八区的警员来帮忙
We've pulled officers from the 3rd and 8th precincts to help.
如果有目击者  我们一定会找到的
If there's a witness out there, we'll find them.
监控录像呢
How about video?
你们发现她车的那个区域
The immediate area where you found her car
没有监控设备覆盖
didn't have any street-cam or security coverage.
简直是绑架的绝佳地点
Making it the perfect place for an abduction.
我派了四区的一组人在查看贝克特被绑时
I have teams from four precincts pulling all video
半径十个街区范围内的所有监控录像
In a 10-block radius from where Beckett was taken.
机会渺茫  不过...
It's a long shot, but...
艾米·巴瑞特呢
What about Amy Barrett...
她打给贝克特的那通电话
The phone call she made to Beckett?
-能追踪吗  -我们试了
- Can we trace that? - We did...
查到一部手机  但已经停止使用了
to a cellphone. It's no longer active.
但我们已经把艾米的照片发给了
But we've got Amy's picture out to every cop
城里的所有警员及交警
and every transit worker in the city.
艾米肯定不会公开露面
Amy's not gonna be in public...
如果她真在跟泰森合作的话
not if she's working with Tyson.
我们推测布德罗就是泰森  可是...
And we're assuming Boudreau is Tyson.But ....
如果
what if
迈克·布德罗真是他自己呢
Mike Boudreau is really Mike Boudreau?
如果是尼曼把他整容成了泰森的样子
What if Nieman actually cut him to look like Tyson
好转移我们的注意力呢
just to give us someone to chase?
如果真正的杰瑞·泰森还在别处逍遥呢
What if the real Jerry Tyson is still out there?
不会
No.
他只是想扰乱我们的思路
He's just messing with our heads.
布德罗就是泰森
Boudreau is Tyson.
这说不通
It doesn't make any sense.
他为什么要让自己被捕
Why would he let himself get arrested?
他为什么要冒险回到自己的公寓
Why would he risk returning to his apartment?
这样刺激
It's part of the thrill.
来到这里
To be here...
跟我们一起  看似唾手可得
a-among us, within our grasp.
他想看他能多么接近火苗
He wants to see how close he can get to the flame.
这就是令他兴奋之处
That's what excites him.
他享受的不只是杀人  更是这场游戏
It's not just the murder he likes... it's the game.
我们抓住了他  然后就放松了警惕
We had him, and we let our guard down.
这就是他的计划
That was his plan.
喂
Hello?
卡塞尔  能听到吗
Castle, can you hear me?
-贝克特  -卡塞尔  我需要你的帮助
- Beckett! - Please, Castle, I need your help.
你在哪
Where are you?
天啊
Oh, God.
卡塞尔  拜托
Castle, please!
你得救我
You have to help me!
卡塞尔  救我
Castle!! Help me!!
号码是多少
What was the number?
212-555-0147
212-555-0147.
-要多久才能追踪到  -不知道
- How long to trace? - Don't know.
听起来她好像在挣扎
It sounded like she was, uh, struggling.
她想逃离什么人
She was trying to get away from someone.
她可能还在那里
She could still be there.
是付费电话  森迪通讯的
It's a payphone... operated by centi-com.
-信号源在哪  -正在追踪
- Where? -Tracing it now.
快啊  快啊
Come on, come on.
有了
Got it.
在上西区  西区高速旁边的停车场
Upper west side... parking lot by the west side highway.
扇形散开  控制周边
Fan out. Secure the area.
这里有东西
There's something here.
看
Look at that.
小心  慢点
Careful. Easy.
可能会爆炸
Might be rigged.
好了
Okay.
是个录音机
It's a voice recorder.
卡塞尔  能听到吗
Castle, can you hear me?
卡塞尔  我需要你的帮助
Please, castle, I need your help.
天啊
Oh, God.
卡塞尔  拜托
Castle, please!
你得救我
You have to help me!
卡塞尔  救我
Castle!! Help me!!
她根本没来过这儿
She was never here.
他在耍我们
He's playing us.
他现在可能正监视着我们呢
He's probably watching us right now.
我要一架直升机
I need a chopper!
我要搜索队搜查所有楼层  行动
I need search teams on every roof! Let's go!
我不明白
I don't understand.
如果这是录音  他们是什么时候录的
If this is a recording, when did they get her to say this?
他们没录  这是伪造的
They didn't... the recording was manufactured,
是用几个不同的音源剪辑拼接在一起的
Digitally spliced from what appear to be several different sources.
什么音源
What sources?
比如  这个
This, for one.
这是你失踪后
It's an interview Beckett gave
贝克特接受本地新闻的一段访问
to the local news just after you disappeared.
拜托  如果您有任何消息
Please, if you have any information
或者知道任何关于理查德·卡塞尔
or know anything about the disappearance
失踪相关的消息  我需要你的帮助
of Richard Castle, I need your help.
这是录音
And here's the recording.
卡塞尔  你能听见吗
Castle, can you hear me?
拜托  卡塞尔  我需要你的帮助
Please, Castle, I need your help.
其中一些话有背景杂音
Given the background noise on some of these other words,
所以我想有一部分是用反射式话筒
I'm guessing parts of this were recorded in public
在公共场所录的
using a parabolic mike on the street,
甚至可能是在一些犯罪现场
Maybe even at crime scenes.
这是计划好的  他们已经准备了好几个月
This was planned. They've been preparing this for months.
看样子是的
Looks that way.
这是为了向贝克特报仇
This was about Beckett.
不
No.
那个采访  那是给...
That interview, that was meant as a...
是给我的一条信息
as a message to me.
他想让我痛苦
He wants me to suffer.
为什么
Why?
泰森为什么咬住你不放
Why is Tyson fixated on you?
如果他是想对付你的话  他或许会联系你
If he's directing this at you, he may try to communicate.
我们应该监听你所有的电话
We should put a tap and a trace on all your phones.
我去安排
I'll set it up.
警监  他已经在跟我交流了
Captain, he's already communicating.
他就在那  躲在布德罗的公寓里
He's out there, sitting in Boudreau's apartment.
而且他知道她在哪
And he knows where she is.
除非我们有证据  否则我们动不了他
And we can't touch him until we have proof.
那时候她就已经死了
By then, she'll be dead!
求你了  警监  这...她是我妻子
Please, Captain. This is... she's my wife.
卡塞尔先生  我知道你很心痛  我们也是
Mr. Castle, I know you're hurting. We all are.
但是我们要保持机敏
But we have to keep our wits about us.
我们要找出证据
We have to work the evidence.
只有这样才能把她救回来
It's the only way we can get her back.
警监
Captain.
在绑架地点排查的警员
The canvass at the abduction site
找到了一名目击者  她说她见到过一个
found a witness who said that she saw someone
符合贝克特特征的人
matching Beckett's description.
她说她坐在轮椅上  被推上了一部红色货车
Said she was in a wheelchair being pushed towards a red van,
目击者还说  她当时好像昏迷了
And, the witness also said she appeared unconscious.
一定是被人下药了
She must've been drugged.
看见和她一起的人了吗
Did they see who was with her?
没有  推轮椅的人戴着帽兜
No. The person pushing the wheelchair was wearing a hoodie.
那车牌号呢
Well, what about a license plate?
没看见
No.
但这就是个开始
But that's a start.
派人查看周围几条街所有的
Get teams scrubbing all street-cam footage
监控摄像头
from blocks nearby.
找出那辆货车
Find that van.
我们会把她救回来的
We are gonna get her back.
不是吧  不是吧  我说了我没有...
No. No, no, no, no. I told you that I'm not --
天哪
Oh, God!
搜索半径
红色货车  30个街区  纽约市
各位
Guys!
这是距贝克特被绑架地点
This is from a traffic camera two blocks away
两个街区外的摄像头拍到的
from where Beckett was taken.
是一辆红色货车
That's a red van.
从绑架地点开过来的
Heading away from the abduction area.
查过车牌了吗
You run the plate?
是皇后区一个水管工的
Belongs to a plumber in Queens.
他在三天前就报失窃了
He reported it stolen three days ago.
一定是这辆车
That's got to be it.
好的  我发全境通告
All right. I'll run an APB.
通知卡塞尔让他知道
Make sure you let Castle know.
好的  他去哪了
Yeah, where is Castle?
她在哪
Where is she?
出去
Get out of here.
她还活着吗
Is she alive?
救命  救命啊
Help! I need help!
放开我  放开我
Get off me! Get off me!
她在哪
Where is she?!
我说了  我不知道
I told you! I don't know!
你为什么要这么做  泰森  报仇吗
Why'd you do it, Tyson? For revenge?
因为我们很幸福吗
Because we were happy?
你找错人了
You have got the wrong guy.
找错才怪
The hell I do.
-她在哪  -我不知道
- Where is she? - I don't know!
你们策划了这一切
You planned this.
你和尼曼
You and Nieman.
不过这一切今晚都会结束
But it ends tonight.
去死吧
Go to hell.
她在哪
Where is she?
不要
No.
冷静  伙计
Hey, hey, m-man.
不要  不要  等等
No, no, no, no, wait a minute.
告诉我她在哪  泰森
Tell me where she is, Tyson,
否则我对天发誓
or so help me, God...
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不是泰森
And I'm not Tyson.
他只是想让你以为我是
He just wants you to think I am.
-她在哪  -不是我做的
- Where is she? - But I didn't do this.
-我什么都做  -她在哪
- I didn't do any of this. - Where is she?
我不是他
I-I'm not him!
尼曼医生把我整形成了他  但我不是
Dr. Nieman just made me look like him, but I'm not him.
她在哪
Where is she?
我叫迈克尔·布德罗  我发誓
My name is Michael Boudreau. I swear.
我出生在爱荷华
I was -- I was born in Iowa.
我在北热那亚街11725号长大
I was raised on 11725 north Genoa street.
我父母是迈克尔和劳伦
My parents' names are Michael and Lauren.
我不是杰瑞·泰森  我不是
I'm -- I'm not Jerry Tyson. I'm not.
我发誓
I swear.
我不信
I don't believe you.
现在
Now...
最后一次机会
last chance.
不不  求你  不要  求求你
No, no. Please. Don't. Don't. Please.
她在哪
Where is she?
纽约警局  警察  把枪放下
NYPD! Police! Drop the gun! Drop it!
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
Drop it!
听到了吗  放下武器
You heard me! Drop the gun now!
把手举起来
Let's see your hands!
拜托  卡塞尔  携带武器袭击他人
Come on, Castle. Assault with a deadly weapon?
你知道这对调查的影响有多大吗
Do you have any idea what this does to the investigation?
你觉得我就不想过去
You don't think I wanted to go over there
揍他一顿吗
and beat the hell out of him --
还有尼曼
and Nieman?
但这没法换她回来
That's not gonna get her back.
他要起诉你
He's pressing charges.
我们必须立案拘留你
We're gonna have to book you.
拘留我
Me?
那他呢
What about him?
我们没证据能拘留他
We don't have anything to hold him on.
你正面跟他冲突是没法取胜的
You were never gonna win going straight at him.
如果他知道你可能成功
If he thought there was any chance of that,
那就绝不会留在公寓
then he wouldn't have stayed in that apartment.
我们稍后再处理拘留的手续
We'll take care of the rest of the booking details later.
-找到货车了吗  -还没
- Anything on the van? - No, not yet.
我第一次来这里时
You know, when I first got here,
简直无法理解贝克特到底喜欢你哪点
I couldn't figure out what Beckett saw in you.
但你知道她是怎么说的吗
But you know what she said?
她说他能看清整个故事
"He sees the story.
我看到的是证据  只能跟着证据走
"I see the evidence, where it leads,
但他能看到整个故事的全局
but he sees the story."
那个人扰乱了你的思维  你让他得逞了
That man got inside your head, and you let him.
你想要救她
You want to help her,
就得潜入他的思维
you got to get inside his.
他在写什么故事
What's his story?
接下来他要做什么
What's his next move going to be?
想明白这个
Now, you figure that out,
我们就能找到她
and we'll find her.
长官
Sir.
怎么了
What's wrong?
是布德罗  泰森
It's Boudreau -- Tyson.
在回公寓的路上
On the way back to his apartment,
他冲下地铁月台跳上了铁轨
He bolted on the subway platform and jumped onto the tracks.
警员试图跟上  结果跟丢了
Our guys tried to follow, but they lost him.
运输管理局全面警戒
I want transit authority on full alert!
把他的照片公布给大家
Put every unit in the area on the lookout
出动所有警力寻找他
and get his picture on the wire!
我要找到他
I want him found!
警监  我刚派了人去凯莉·尼曼家
Captain, I just sent teams to Kelly Nieman's apartment
查看她的状况
to check on her.
她不见了
She's gone.
她怎么会不见  我们一直在盯着她的呀
How can she be gone? We've been on her place the whole time.
他们发现了条通向楼顶的通道
They found an access door to the roof open.
她肯定是从哪里跑了出去
She must have went out of it
从楼顶爬去了其他建筑物
and climbed across the roof to another building.
发全境通告找她  派人去医院
Get an APB out on her and get teams down to the hospital...
喂
Hello?
差点成功的感觉如何啊
How did it feel to be that close?
泰森
Tyson.
追踪  快
Trace -- go.
你知道我最喜欢哪部分吗
You know the part I liked best?
就是你眼里流露的痛
The pain in your eyes.
满是苦楚
The suffering.
还有恐惧  因为知道她就在我手里
And all that fear, knowing that I have her.
如果你是冲我来的  那就带我走
Well, if this is about me, then take me.
带我走  放了她
Take me and let her go.
不行
No.
如果带走你  我只能杀死你一次
No, if I took you, I'd only get to kill you once.
但现在这样
See, this way,
我可以让你生不如死
I get to kill you over and over again.
泰森
Tyson.
Tyson?
莱恩
Ryan?
-找到他了吗  -等待中
- Did you get him? - Stand by.
等等
Wait. Wait.
找到了  号码马上就能查到
Got it! Number's coming through right now!
他是从哪打的电话
Where's he calling from?
天哪
Oh, god.
卡塞尔
Castle?
他是从你家打来的
He's calling from your house.
阿丽克西斯呢
Where's Alexis?
爸爸  怎么回事啊
Dad, what the hell?!
带护照了吗
You have your passport?
带了带了  但是必须去欧洲吗
Yes, yes, yes. But, Richard, Europe?
不要说"但是"  我必须确保你们的安全
No "Buts." I need to know that you're safe.
警察会送你们去机场
Now, the -- the police are gonna take you to the airport.
-我会让朋友在到达站接机  -好
- I have friends waiting for you on the other side. - Okay.
爸  一定要保重
Dad, please be safe.
我会的  但你们必须走
I will. But I need you to go.
好吧  保重  孩子
Okay. Take care, baby.
保重
Be careful.
我爱你
I love you.
技术部刚传来消息
We just heard from tech.
没有发现你的电话被篡改的证据
No evidence of anyone tampering with your phone.
他们觉得泰森找到了一个法子
They think that Tyson must have figured out a way
远程仿制了你的电话号码
to spoof your number from the outside.
入室篡改还是远程控制  并不重要
Inside, outside -- doesn't matter.
他想让我知道他随时都能威胁到我
He wants me to know he can get to me anytime.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
那晚在汽车旅馆我本有机会
I had him the night at the motel.
如果我动作能再快些
I-if I could have found a way to move a little faster,
反应再快一秒...
react a second sooner...
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
也是我的错
It's not my fault.
是他的错
It's his fault.
皇后区的警察刚看到了通缉的红色失窃货车
Uniform in Queens just spotted that stolen red van off the APB.
在哪儿
Where?
停在一个废弃工业设施的外面
Parked outside of an abandoned industrial property.
-她在那儿吗  -不知道
- Is she there? - We don't know.
但特警队正在赶去
But an E.S.U. Team's on its way.
我有发现  三楼
I got something -- third floor.
是她
It's her.
人质已识别  在三楼东北角
We have a positive I.D. -- third floor, northeast corner.
-还有多少人  -不清楚  不在可视范围内
- How many others? - Unknown. We don't have a visual.
跟我们后面  如果他在里头  他会最先杀你
Stay behind us. If he's in there, he's gonna gun for you first.
卡塞尔  别动  退后  这是个陷阱
Castle! Wait! Get back! It's a trap!
小心
Watch out!
贝克特  不
Beckett!! No!!
天哪
God!
凯特  真抱歉
Kate, I'm so sorry.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我真
I'm so--
这不是她
It's not her!
不是她
那女孩是谁
Who was the girl?
像其他人一样  以前是个吸毒者
Former drug addict, just like the others.
上周被报失踪
She was reported missing last week.
他们在椅子下面找到了一个扬声器
They found a speaker underneath the chair.
这样他能播放贝克特的声音
It's how he was able to broadcast Beckett's voice.
武器呢
And the weapon?
预先对准了被害人  远程触发
Pre-aimed at the victim, triggered remotely.
他想让我们看着
He wanted us to watch.
你觉得她还活着吗
You think she's still alive?
她活着
She's alive.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为他和我的恩怨还没有了结
Because he's not done with me yet.
好
Good.
你醒了
You're awake.
我们可以开始了
We can get started.
最近的被害人叫希德妮·诺瓦克
Our new victim's name is Sydney Novak,
来自佛罗里达州布劳沃德县
from Broward county, Florida.
我们认为她被泰森和尼曼选中
We believe she may have been targeted by Tyson and Nieman
是因为她和贝克特警长的
due to facial similarities
脸部特征相似
between her and detective Beckett.
鉴于这些谋杀案的特性
Given the nature of these murders...
我们找不到她的
We're not gonna find her.
不能用这种方式
Not like this.
不能只是追逐他  按他的模式来
Not by chasing him, not by playing his game.
我们需要设局让他来玩
We need to take the game to him.
我认识你
I know you.
你是那个作家
You're the writer.
是你和你的警察朋友把我关起来的
You and your cop friend put me in here.
是因为你的狱友杰瑞·泰森
For murders that your cellmate Jerry Tyson
让你犯下的那些罪行
convinced you to commit
这样全世界都认为你是3XK
so the world would think you were 3XK
他就能逍遥法外了
and he would get away scot-free.
你来这干什么
Why are you here?
四年里你和他同住一间牢房
You shared a cell with him for four years.
我宁愿忘记那几年
Time I'd rather forget.
为什么
Why?
你看着他会觉得  他太弱了
You look at him, you think..."he's so weak."
一无是处
There's nothing to him.
但他知道怎么掌控你
But the guy -- he knew how to get in your head.
他知道怎样让你做
He knew how to make you do things
你以为自己不会做的事
you never thought capable of.
比如说帮他杀人吗
Like killing for him?
我只想说  自从得知他的死讯
Let's just say I slept a lot better
我终于睡得安稳了
once I knew he was dead.
他没死
He's not.
他只是消失了一阵
Just another way for him to disappear
计划新的行动
so he could make his plans.
他还活着
He's alive?
我妻子在他手上
And he has my wife.
你跟他同住一间牢房四年
You shared a cell with him for four years.
没人比你更了解他
No one knows him better than you.
四年中
In all that time,
他有没提过城里的某个地方
did he ever mention a place somewhere in the city,
能让他有安全感
a place he would go to feel safe?
你需要我的帮助
You need my help.
没错我需要你的帮助
Yes, I need your help.
你把我关进大牢
You put me in here.
是他干的
He put you in here.
是他让你做了那些事
He got you to do those things.
他看透了你  把你像傀儡一样控制
He got inside your head, controlled you like a puppet.
你已经付出代价了  但我们需要你来抓住他
You'd done your time, but he needed you to get caught.
你牺牲了自己
You sacrificed yourself.
我猜你每晚都会看到他的脸
And I bet not a night goes by you don't see his face
琢磨"他是怎么做到的
and wonder, "How did he do that?
他是怎么让我放弃自己生活的"
How did he get me to throw my life away?"
他说过一个地方
There was some place he talked about --
一个他喜欢去的地方
a place he liked to go.
在哪
Where?
我有什么好处
What's in it for me?
你想要什么
What do you want?
出狱
Out.
你知道我没这权力
You know I don't have the authority --
我确定凭借你的人脉
I'm sure with all your connections,
能找到可以放我出去的人
you can find someone who does.
他们不会同意的
They'll never go for it.
他们不会释放谋杀犯  他们会让她去死
Not gonna release a murderer. They'll let her die first.
这与我无关
That's not my problem.
求你了
Please.
你提别的要求吧
Something else.
给你家里人钱
Money for your family.
提我办得到的要求
Give me something I can give you.
我没有家人  卡塞尔
I don't have a family, mr. Castle.
我余生都要在这度过
And I am stuck in here for life
也没有假释的可能
without the possibility of parole,
所以你觉得你能给我
so what the hell do you think you could give me
什么有价值的东西
that would be worth a damn?
复仇
Revenge.
他在外面无拘无束  你却被关在这里
He's out there, walking around, and you're in here.
你不想报仇雪恨吗
Don't you want to settle the score?
我真没想到过了那么多年
Fine. Guess I just didn't think, after all these years,
你还是任他摆布
you'd still let him control you.
怎么复仇
What kind of revenge?
他提过一个地方
There was a place he talked about --
树林里的一幢房子
A house in the woods.
在哪
Where?
在哈德逊河上游  房子是他家人朋友的
A little ways up the Hudson, owned by a family friend.
小时候  如果跟母亲关系紧张
When he was a kid, he'd go there in the summers
一到夏天他就会去那
when things got too intense with his mother.
你好  你们有电子历史记录吗
Hello. Are your archives digitized?
能否给我电邮一份
I was wondering if you could e-mail me
以下地址的建筑平面图
a set of the building plans for the following address.
你救不了她
You know, you can't save her.
他一看到警察来
When he sees the cops coming --
相信我  他看得到
and, trust me, he will see the cops coming --
他不会讨价还价
he won't bargain.
不会讲道理
He won't be reasoned with.
他只会
He will just...
杀了她
kill her.
警察不会去
It won't be the cops.
去的人是我
It'll be me.
艾米·巴瑞特
Amy Barrett.
你觉得巴瑞特与这事有关
You think Barrett was involved in this?
或者她也是受害者
Or she's a victim, too.
她的确在和他们合作
So she was working with them.
别叫  要不我开枪了
Don't scream, or I will shoot you.
贝克特在哪  她在房子里吗
Where's Beckett? Is she inside the house?
她在哪
Where is she?
不在这
Not here.
在哪
Where?
我不知道  他们没告诉我
I don't know. They wouldn't tell me.
一切结束后我才会知道
Not until it's over.
他们让我在这等着
They sent me here to wait.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
还有谁  谁在房子里
Who's down there? Who's in the house?
只有我
Just me.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
他们都在里面  对吧
They're in there, aren't they?
没在
No.
不信你带我回去看
If you bring me back there, I'll show you.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
确保你不妨碍我做事
Making sure you stay out of my way.
你知道我最喜欢这车哪点吗
You know what I love about this car?
它宽敞的后备箱
All the trunk space.
进去
Get in.
如果我说谎  他们真的在那
If I'm lying and they are down there,
他们会发现我不见了
they're gonna miss me soon.
他们会知道你在  会杀了你俩
They'll know you're out here. They'll kill you both.
尽管落得如此下场  我还是很敬佩你
Despite the situation, I want you to know I admire you.
一直如此
I always have.
反抗是没有意义的  探长
There's no point in resisting, detective.
事实上  如果你接受  我把塞口物解开
If fact, if you accept that, I can remove the gag.
很好
Good.
别尖叫  没用
And please don't scream. It's tedious.
没人能听见
And no one can hear you.
好多了
Much better.
遮住这么美丽的脸庞简直是犯罪
It's a crime to cover up such a lovely face.
绑架和谋杀才是犯罪
Kidnapping and murder are crimes.
你还可以自救
You can still save yourself.
我已经被拯救了
I've already been saved.
我曾为内心真实的自我
I used to feel ashamed of who I was inside,
那些我想做的事情而感到羞耻
the things I dreamt about doing.
后来我遇见了杰瑞
And then I met Jerry,
那感觉就像是找到了归宿
And it was like... coming home.
如果你觉得我会背叛他
So if you think that I would ever turn on him,
你根本就不了解我
You don't understand me at all.
当你没有利用价值的时候
What do you think he's gonna do
你认为他会怎么处置你
when you're no longer useful to him?
他会杀了你
He will kill you.
我是你唯一的机会  凯莉  我能帮你
I am your only chance, Kelly. I can help you.
你马上就会帮到
And you're going to.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
警察盯上我们了  我需要一张新脸
With all the police attention, I'll need a new face.
我选了你的
And I've chosen yours.
不
No.
不要  求你了
No! Please!
求你了
Please.
-还是给你戴上吧  -不要
- This is going back on. - No!
她不在这
She's not here.
但你在
But you are.
你能来我很高兴
So glad you could join me.
脸庞让我着迷
Faces fascinate me.
我们展现给世人的面具
The mask we show to the world.
我发现客户总是希望手术
I find that clients invariably hope
不但能改变外表
a procedure won't just change their looks,
还能改变他们内心的本质
but change who they are in some deeper way.
哪有那种事
Never does.
仅仅是粉刷房子
Any more than painting a house
怎能改变房子里发生的事情
can change the things that happen inside of it.
什么事
Yes?
逮到他了吗
Do you have him?
是的
Yeah, I've got him.
你从她身上拿到需要的东西了吗
Did you get what you need from her?
足够了
Enough.
其他事可以之后再办
I can do the rest after.
给她准备好
Get her ready.
等我的电话
Wait for my call.
一切很快就会结束
It'll all be over soon.
但我很享受我们一切相处的时光
But I've so enjoyed our time together.
坐
Take a seat.
求你
Please.
我在你手里  放了她
You have me now. Just let her go.
不行
Oh, no, no, no. I can't.
她是计划的一部分
She's part of the plan.
我为什么把你带到这来
Why I brought you here.
带我来
Brought me?
你知道我最喜欢人类的哪一点吗
You know what I love about human beings?
他们可预知性太强  就像老鼠一样
Is they're so predictable. They're like mice.
你能让他们做任何事
You can get them to do anything.
你只需
All you have to do
在迷宫尽头放一小块芝士
is put a little cheese at the end of the maze
知道什么时候惊吓它们就行
and know exactly when to shock them.
你知道我会来
You knew I was coming.
以布德罗身份  在你面前晃悠
Dangling Boudreau in front of you,
眼看贝克特在眼前死去
watching Beckett die before your eyes --
当我把警察玩得团团转之时
Once I had the cops chasing their tails,
我知道你决定自己出手
I knew it'd be only a matter of time
只是时间问题
before you did something on your own.
拜访我的狱友
Visiting my old cellie was a --
是很合乎情理的选择
well, that was a natural choice.
这是个圈套
This was a setup.
把你单独引来的最好方法
What better way to get you here alone
就是让你以为你是自己找来的
than to make you think it was your idea?
为什么
Why?
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this to me?
因为我想看着你的脸
Because I want to see your face.
所以我才会把你引到这
It's why I lured you here --
这样我就能在她死掉时
so I could see your face...
欣赏你脸上的表情
while you watched her die.
不
No.
不是因为这个
That's not it.
这跟我无关  对吧
This isn't about me, is it?
远不止这么简单
Oh, it's about so much more than that.
这跟你有关
This is about you.
你的弱点
Your inadequacy.
所有的游戏  所有的摆布
All the games, all the manipulation...
在我毁掉了你的计划之后
After I screwed up your plans,
你需要证明你比我聪明
you needed to prove you were smarter than me.
你要知道你能控制我
You needed to know you could control me.
可你来了啊
Well, you're here.
我写过你这样的角色
You know, I've written characters like you.
机智的反社会主义者  如此自恋
Cunning psychopaths so narcissistic,
他们认为自己不会被抓
they believe they can't be caught -
因为他们比别人聪明
Because they're smarter than everyone
他们还需要证明这一点
and they need to prove it.
那是你的故事  杰瑞
That's your story, Jerry.
你所作所为的原因
Why you did everything.
你要证明这一切
You needed to prove it.
于是我就让你得手了
So I let you.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我任由你把我引到这里
I let you bring me here.
这是找到你的唯一方法
It's the only way to find you.
我找到你才能找到她
I needed to find you so I could find her.
但事实是  杰瑞
But the truth, Jerry...
我们找不到她的  不能用这种方式
We're not gonna find her -- not like this.
不能只是追逐他  按他的模式来
Not by chasing him, not by playing his game.
我们需要设局让他来玩
We need to take the game to him.
把这个放进耳朵深处
Put this deep in your ear.
全放进去
All right? All the way in.
事实是
The truth is...
我引你来这
I lured you here...
看你死
to watch you die.
清楚了吗[准备好了吗]
Are we clear?
清楚什么
Clear about what?
那就开枪吧
Then take the shot.
瑞恩  他倒下了
Ryan, he's down.
你找到她的所在地了吗
You have her location?
是的
Yeah.
这呢
Here.
这是他最近打过的号码
This is the last number he called.
贝克特和尼曼在一起
Beckett's with Nieman.
我需要紧急追踪以下号码
I need an emergency trace on the following number...
出问题了
Something's wrong.
这个时候他应该打来了
He should have called by now.
恐怕是时候了  探长
I'm afraid it's time, detective.
那边
There!
贝克特
Beckett?
我吓坏了
I was so scared.
-你还好吗  -是的
- You okay? - Yeah.
那是你干过最愚蠢  最冒失
That was the stupidest, most reckless,
最不负责任的事  卡塞尔先生
irresponsible stunt you've ever pulled, Mr. Castle.
谢谢你
Thank you.
好了  好了
Okay. All right, all right, all right.
好啦
Okay!
不过我们还要处理伤人的指控
There's still the matter of the assault charges.
伤人的指控
Assault charges?
说来话长
Uh, it's a -- it's a long story.
不过警监  你是开玩笑吧
But, c-captain you can't be serious.
不管他是不是连环杀手
Serial killer or no,
你都持枪威胁了一个手无寸铁的男子
you threatened an unarmed man with a gun.
地检官对这事态度很坚决
The D.A. takes that very seriously.
但
But...
鉴于你在此案优异的表现
in light of your outstanding work on this case,
你如果同意1000小时
He's willing to drop the charges
社区服务性劳役  他同意撤销指控
if you agree to 1,000 hours of community service.
1000小时
1,000 hours?!
是的
Yes.
作为12分局和贝克特探长
As a consultant to detective beckett
的顾问
and the 12th precinct.
我
I'm -- I'm -- I'm --
我被解禁了
I'm being un-banned?
卡塞尔先生  欢迎回来
Mr. Castle, welcome back.
好了
Okay!
那是我母亲和阿莱克西斯
That was my mother and Alexis.
买完东西
They said they're on their way home,
她们就上路
just as soon as they do some shopping.
我真不知道你是怎么做到的
I don't know how you did it.
做到什么
What?
在我失踪两个月期间没有逼疯
Kept it together the two months I was missing.
两天找不到你
Two days, I didn't know where you were,
我就已经生不如死
and it nearly killed me.
你有想过发生的事吗
You ever think about what happened...
你失踪时的事
when you were gone?
总在想
All the time.
我一闭眼  就能看到她的脸
Every time I close my eyes, I see her face.
我也看得到他的
I see his, too.
自从桥上那晚
Since that night on the bridge.
知道我如何应对吗
You know how I deal with it?
不知道
No.
睁开眼  看着你
I open my eyes and look at you.
谢谢你来救我
Thanks for coming to get me.
我会一如既往
Always.